American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IId. 1837-1844 APS.Archives.IId APS.Archives.IId
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to John Vaughan, August 1, 1838; 8" x 10"; Boston Society of Natural History
    [Boston], 1 p. and address. Pr.D.S. Statement of purposes of the Society's Journal.
  - Receipt to John Vaughan for payment for fossil bones, Aug. 10, 1838; 4-1/2x7-1/2; Grant & Stone
    Philadelphia, D.S. 1p.,end.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, August 13, 1838; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Troost, Gerard, 1776-1850
    Librarian of A.P.S., Nashville, Tenn., 2 pp. address and endorsement. A.L.S. Inquires whether the A.P.S. would publish some of his memoirs, which, hitherto, he has been obliged to publish in France. Not found May, 2011.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred the letter of Dr. Gerard Troost to [John] Vaughan, August 13, October 5, 1838; 7 7/8" x 12 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    dated in re a series of papers on geology, [Philadelphia], 3 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: Franklin Bache, J[ohn] K. Kane, R[obert] M. Patterson. Publication declined.
  - Letter to H[einrich] C[hristian] Schumaker, Aug. 14, 1838; 10x8; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. Letterpress copy. 1p. (see Ms.comm.to the APS. Natural philosophy, vol. 2, no. 91.) Asks for missing issues of an almanac. Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 15, 1838; 10x8; Walker, Sears Cook, 1805-1853
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and end. (see Ms. comm.to the APS. Natural philosophy, vol. 2 no. 90.) Asks for almanacs to be ordered for him. Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 27, 1838; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Hubbard, David, 1792-1874
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.,end.and add. States that Hawkins' sketch of the Creek Indians is is extremely accurate. Refers to the APS.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, August 28, 1838; 8" x 10"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests Vaughan to order W. H. Medhurst's books from Batavia, for the A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to J[oh]n Vaughan, Philadelphia, Aug. 28, 1838; 9x5-1/2; Rümker, Carl, 1788-1862
    Hamburg observatory, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see Ms.comm to the APS. Natural philosophy, vol.2, no. 92.) Concerning astronomical observations. Not found May, 2011.
  - Invoice of books purchased in Paris for the American philosophical society, Aug. 31, 1838; 12-1/2x8; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    [received,]. A.D. 2p.,end.by John Vaughan.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 3, 1838; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p. and address. A.N.S. Forwards a packet from the Royal Society [of London] to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 7, 1838; 7 3/4" x 9 1/2"; Stoughton, F.
    Librarian of A.P.S., New York, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Acknowledges letter of August 29. Has forwarded package to Royal Academy of History at Madrid.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 9, 1838; 7 15/16" x 9 7/8"; Hon-non-de-uh
    Seneca Nation, Buffalo, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Returns book he had borrowed. Offers to send copies of all books published in Seneca language to A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 10, 1838; 9-1/2x8; Davis, John Philip, 1784-1862
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Forwards Prescott's new volume.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 14, 1838; 6 15/16" x 8 13/16"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Librarian of A.P.S., Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Wishes a copy of the new history of Maryland, Marshall's History of Kentucky, and Haywood's History of Tennessee.
  - Letter to P[eter] S[tephen] DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Sept. 17, 1838; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Académie royale des sciences, des lettres et des beaux-arts de Belgique
    Brussels, D.S.: Quetelet. 1p.,end.and add. In French. Thanks for publication.
  - Report of committee on E. O[tis] Kendall's paper on the longitude [as calculated] from the solar eclipse of, September 18, 1838 - November 15, 1839; 7 7/8" x 12 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: R[obert] M. Patterson, Geo[rge] M. Justice, A[lexander] D[allas] Bache. Publication recommended. Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, Sept. 19, 1838; 10x8-1/4; Magyar Tudományos Akadémia
    Budapest, L.S.: Francois [Ferenz] Schedel (Toldy). 1p. In French. Thanks for publications.
  - Comments by Peter Stephen Du Ponceau on the advisibility of the Society's acquiring certain books on languages, forwarded by Mr. Pickering, of Boston, Sept. 21, 1838; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
  - Notes of experiments made Aug. 22 to 25 by Professor C.Bonnycastle of the U. of Virginia - & Dr. R.M. Patterson - with the view of determining the depth of the sea by the echo, Sept. 21, 1838; 8x6; Bonnycastle, Charles, 1792-1840
    D. 6p.and end. See Proceedings, I, 39-41. Printed: Annals of Science, vol.10,no.1,March 1954,pp-28-32. Film 403 Frame 28
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Sept. 21, 1838; 7 7/8" x 9 15/16"; Penington, John, 1799-1867
    Librarian of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Offers to sell four books, which he imported from Germany, to the A.P.S. "at the prices of importation."
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 22, 1838; 10x8; Zoological Society of London
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wm.Rees. 1p.,end. Thanks for Transactions. Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 23, 1838; 7 11/16" x 9 13/16"; Prescott, William Hickling, 1796-1859
    Boston, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: a new edition of the History of Ferdinand and Isabella.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 25, 1838; 8 1/2" x 12 1/8"; Navarrete, Martín Fernández de, 1765-1844
    Librarian of the A.P.S., Madrid, 1 p. and endorsement. L.S. (In Spanish.)
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 26, 1838; 10x8; Académie royale des sciences, des lettres et des beaux-arts de Belgique
    Brussels, L.S.: Quetelet. 2p. and add. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to Richard Harlan, September 27, 1838; 7 5/8" x 12"; Hullihen, S. P. (Simon P.), 1810-1857
    Wheeling, 2 pp., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Account of inscription on a stone at Grave Creek Mound, near Wheeling. See Pro., I, 46.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Sept. 28, 1838; 8x5; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    A.L.S.with initials. 1p. William C. Frazer presents a translation of the New Testament into the Chippewa language, by Edwin James, of Albany. For publication, see: 225.5971:K26.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 28, 1838; 9-3/4x8-1/4; Society of Antiquaries of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Nicholas Carlisle. 1p.and add.: "by favour of Wm.Vaughan,Esq" Thanks for Transactions. Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, Sept. 28, 1838; Zoological Society of London
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 30, 1838; 8 3/16" x 11 5/8"; Navarrete, Martín Fernández de, 1765-1844
    Librarian of A.P.S., Madrid, 1 p. and endorsements. L.S. (In Spanish.)
  - Letter to F[ranklin] Bache, October 2, 1838; 7 7/8" x 10"; Nisbet, Michael
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Offers Copley medal to Benjamin Franklin to the A.P.S. for $500. FILM54-61 FRAME134
  - Donations to A[merican] P[hilosophical] Soc[iet]y, October 5, 1838; 6 1/4" x 7 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. D. List of societies and individuals who made donations to the A.P.S. library. See Pro., I, 42-43.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred the paper of Mr. E[ugenius] Nulty, October 5, 1838; 7 7/8" x 12 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    entitled "New formulae relative to comets," [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: Robert] M. Patterson, Sears G. Walker, A[ndrew] Talcott. Recommend publication in Transactions. See Pro., I, 43.
  - Concerning William C. Frazer's report on Indian ruins in Wisconsin, Oct. 5, 1838; 5x8; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    A.D. 1p. Draft. For finished report, see APS Minutes for date.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred the letter of Dr. Gerard Troost... in re a series of papers on geology, Oct. 5, 1838; American Philosophical Society
  - Letter to Franklin Bache, October 6, 1838; 8" x 10"; Harris, Levett
    Secretary of A.P.S., Paris, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. With reference to the foreign members of the A.P.S. (2 pp. list enclosed.)
  - Receipt to J[oh]n Vaughan for a credit for the society on Mr. Richards for Prinseps of Calcutta, Oct. 8, 1838; 3x6-1/2; Oakford, Richard
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Rd.Oakford for Jacob R.Elfreth. 1p.and end.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Oct. 8, 1838; 5x8; Silliman, Benjamin, 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to Jo[h]n Vaughan, Philadelphia, Oct. 8, [1838]; 10x8; Davis, John Philip, 1784-1862
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Prescott will send new edition of his work to the APS. Favorable reception in England.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, October 13, 1838; 8" x 10"; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Princeton, 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Has observed eclipse in company with Mr. Alexander. Will give account to A.P.S. as soon as possible. FILM 235 FRAME 5 Work on electrical experiments.
  - Letter to Magyar Tudományos Akadémia Konyvtára, Oct. 16, 1838; 9-1/2x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, Xerox of A.L.S.: John Vaughan. 1p.and end (From original in Magyar Tudományos Akadémia Konyvtára; 1968.) Forwards publications by Charles Nagy.
  - Report of the committee appointed to consider the expediency of the Society forming an American association for the promotion of the sciences, October 16, 1838; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: W[illiam] E. Horner and four others. Plan considered inexpedient.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, October 17, 1838; 4 7/8" x 8"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, 1 p. A.L.S. Advises sending a dozen or two copies of A.P.S. Hist. Trans. II to Hamburg.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, October 22, 1838; 7 1/4" x 9"; Leslie, Charles Robert, 1794-1859
    President of the A.P.S., London, 2pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to ----, Oct. 26, 1838; 10x8; Prichard, James C. Cowles, 1786-1848
    Bristol, Eng.; L. 1p. Extract. Copy. Concerning the languages of Brittany and Wales. Read before the APS; Nov. 16, 1838.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred the letter from S. P. Hullihen to Dr. [Richard] Harlan, November 2, 1838; 8" x 9"; American Philosophical Society
    in re inscription on a stone found at Grave Creek, near Wheeling, Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Peter S. DuPonceau, Robley Dunglison. Publication in Transactions recommended.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 2, 1838; 8 1/8" x 10 3/8"; Morelli, Chevalier Domenico de
    Librarian of the A.P.S., Naples, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Sends to A.P.S.: Royal Museum Borbonicum, X and XI.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 2, 1838; 8 1/8" x 10 3/8"; Morelli, Chevalier Domenico de
    Librarian of the A.P.S., Naples, 1 p. and endorsement. Sends end of vol. V and beginning of vol. VI, Universal Italian Dictionary.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 3, 1838; 10x8; Academia Real das Sciencias de Lisboa
    L.S.: Macedo. 1p. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 3, 1838; 10x8; Royal Asiatic Society of Great Britain and Ireland
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: John Briggs. 1p.,end.and add.: Care of W.Vaughan. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to the [American] philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 7, 1838; 10x8; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Josiah Quincy, pres., and Thaddeus William Harris, Librarian. 1p.,end.and add.: Care of Peter S. DuPonceau. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 8, 1838; 15x9; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: William J. Hamilton. 1p.,end.and add.: To the care of William Vaughan Esq. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to Richard Harlan, November 10, 1838; 7 3/4" x 10"; Townsend, Thomas
    Com-1 Wheeling, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. With regard to a paper he is preparing upon an inscription found on a stone in Grave Creek Mound, near Wheeling.
  - Report of the committee appointed on a paper by Dr. [Robert] Hare giving an account of the tornado at Providence, November 16, 1838; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    R. I., [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsements. D.S.: A[lexander] D[allas] Bache, R[obert] M. Patterson, J. P. Espy. Recommend publication in Transactions.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, Nov. 16, 1838; Berlin. Akademie der wissenschaften.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 17, 1838; 9x7-1/2; Cambridge Philosophical Society
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.S.Newslow. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 17, 1838; 9x7-1/4; Cambridge Philosophical Society
  - Letter to Franklin Bache, November 20, 1838; 7 3/4" x 10"; Townsend, Thomas
    Wheeling, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Desires to know whether the "American Antiquarian Society" will publish an article on the mound at the mouth of Grave Creek.
  - Letter to William E. Horner, November 20, 1838; 7 7/8" x 9 1/2"; Warren, John Collins, 1778-1856
    Boston, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests cooperation of A.P.S. in the formation of the American Association for the Cultivation of Science.
  - Letter to A[lexander] D[allas] Bache, November 23, 1838; 7 7/8" x 10"; Hodge, Hugh L. (Hugh Lenox), 1796-1873
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Will present an obituary notice of Dr. James to the A.P.S. within the ensuing month.
  - Letter to A[lexander] D[allas] Bache, December 3, 1838; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Sparks, Jared, 1789-1866
    Secretary of A.P.S., Cambridge, Mass., 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Accepts appointment to prepare a biographical notice of the late Dr. [Abiel] Holmes.
  - Letter to A[lexander] D[allas] Bache, December 5, 1838; 8" x 9 7/8"; Gilpin, Henry D. (Henry Dilworth), 1801-1860
    Secretary of A.P.S., Washington, 1p. and endorsement. A.L.S. With regard to obituary notices of Mr.[Edward] Livingston and Mr.[James] Brown.
  - Report... Philadelphia, December 7, 1838; 7 15/16" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society. Committee on publications
    2 pp. and endorsements. D.S.: Isaac Lea, Isaac Hays, J[oshua] Francis Fisher.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 12, 1838; 7" x 8 13/16"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Librarian of A.P.S., Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Has paid subscription for designated journals for A.P.S.; Professor [Joseph] Henry; and [William B.] Hodgson. FILM235 FRAME36
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec. 15, 1838; 10x8; Royal Asiatic Society of Great Britain and Ireland
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Edwin Norris. 1p. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, December 16, 1838; 8 1/8" x 10 5/8"; Eyriès, Alexandre
    Havre, 1 p. and address. L.S. (In French.) Renders to Peter S. DuPonceau account of expenses for sending cases to Mr. [D. B.] warden in Paris.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 17, 1838; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Brigham, William, 1806-1869
    Librarian of the A.P.S., Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Sends to the A.P.S. a copy of a lecture by Dr. Channing.
  - Receipt to the American philosophical society for expenses, Dec. 17, 1838; 10x7-1/2; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    D.S.: Jacob Snider, jr. 1p.and end.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 19, 1838; 8" x 10"; Barclay and Livingston
    New York, 1p. and address. L.s. Acknowledges receipt of letter and parcel for Lisbon.
  - Report of the committee on the paper of Professor [Joseph] Henry upon electricity, December 20, 1838; 7 5/8" x 9"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. D.S.: R[obert] M. Patterson, Rob[er]t Hare, A[lexander] D[allas] Bache. Publication recommended.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 20, 1838; 15x8; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Cha[rle]s Darwin. 1p.and add. Thanks for Proceedings. (Original in APS Archives; xerox as Carroll no.13.)
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, December 20, 1838; 8" x 9 7/8"; Thayer, Sylvanus, 1785-1872
    Librarian of A.P.S., Boston, 1p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of letter of August 26. Wishes to complete his set of A.P.S. Transactions. FILM 403 FRAME 13-3
  - Report of the committee appointed on the papers of Dr. [Robert] Hare... [Philadelphia], December 21, 1838; 8" x 10 1/8"; American Philosophical Society
    1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Franklin Bache, A[lexander] D[allas] Bache, Isaiah Lukens. Recommends three papers for publication in the Transactions.
  - Report... [Philadelphia], December 21, 1838; 7 3/4" x 9 3/8"; American Philosophical Society. Committee on finance
    1 p. and endorsements. D.S.: Clement C. Biddle, R[obert] M. Patterson.
  - Report of committee on Isaac Lea's paper, Dec. 21, 1838 - March 5, 1841; 8x8; American Philosophical Society
    read before the society on D.S.: Philip H. Nicklin, Isaac Hays. 1p. Se A.P.S. Proceedings, vol. II, 30. Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 26, 1838; 10x8; Zoological Society of London
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wm.Rees. 1p.,end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Account with the American philosophical society, Dec. 31, 1838 - Nov. 30, 1839; 10x8; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    D.S.: R.R. Robb. 1p.and end.
  - Original notes of M. de la Palun on Father Morrone's Cochinchinese vocabulary., [1838]; 8" x 9 3/4"; La Palun, de
    ca. vi,31p. [10]pl. In French. Deposited by P.S. DuPonceau Feb. 16, 1838. Material used by DuPonceau in his Dissertation on...Chinese system of writing, 1838. See Transactions of Historical and literary committee of A.P.S., v.2,1838, p.139. Bequest of P.S. DuPonceau; 3 May 1844.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 2, 1839; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Biddle, Nicholas, 1786-1844
    ----, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Announcing coming visit of the Seignora Vespucci to the library of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 3, 1839; 7 13/16 x 9 3/4; Godon, Victor L.
    Secretary of A.P.S., Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p., add., end. Donates ibis, excavated in Egypt, to the American Philosophical Society. (Prev. cataloged as Jan.3, 1838.)
  - Report of the committee to which was referred the "Contributions to the geology of the tertiary formations of Virginia,", January 4, 1839; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    by W[illia]m B. Rogers and Henry D. Rogers, [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Isaac Lea, Isaac Hays. Publication in Transactions recommended.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 4, 1839; 8" x 10"; Hewson, Thomas T.
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.N.S. Tenders his resignation from the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 4, 1839; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Prescott, William Hickling, 1796-1859
    Boston, 3 pp., address and endorsement. L.S. Requests that a set of A.P.S. Transactions be sent to him. Article on DuPonceau, by John Pickering, in The North American Review.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 9, 1839; 7 5/8" x 9 3/4"; DeKay, James E.
    New York Historical Society, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Asks that Mr. H. Eckford be granted permission to transcribe the copy of De Vries Voyages in possession of A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 11, 1839; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Prescott, William Hickling, 1796-1859
    Boston, 2 pp. and address. L.S. Wishes only new series of A.P.S. Transactions and Transactions of Historical and Literary committee. Success of Ferdinand and Isabella.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 14, 1839; 7 13/16" x 9 11/16"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    Treasurer of A.P.S., London, 1 p. and address. L.S. Forwards information obtained from Captain Beaufort concerning light houses in the British Isles and France to [F. R.] Hassler and the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 14, 1839; 7" x 8 7/8"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Has paid subscriptions for the journals for this and the last year. Has delivered to Mr. Bertrand the numbers till the close of the year for the A. P. S. and Professor [Joseph] Henry. FILM235 FRAME37
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, January 14, 1839; 8 3/8" x 10 3/8"; de Wette, L. L-5
    Librarian of A.P.S., Basel, Switzerland, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Forwards publications of [Basel] Society for Natural History.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Jan. 18, 1839; 10x8; Rönne, Friedrich Ludwig v., 1795-1865
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.,end. In French. Forwards thanks of the Prussian king for the APS publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 21, 1839; 10x8; Kentucky Historical Society
    Louisville, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Edward Jarvis. 1p. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 24, 1839; 8" x 9 7/8"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and address. A.L.Initialled. Sends Vaughan L'Art de verifier les dates, XVI, together with some pamphlets sent from France by [D. B.] Warden.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], Philadelphia, Jan. 26, 1839; 10-1/2x8; Académie des sciences (France)
    Paris, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: flourens. 1p.and add. and end. In French. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 9, 1839; 7" x 8 7/8"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Librarian of A.P.S., Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Acknowledges receipt of draft for 824 francs, due him from the Foreign Library of Philadelphia. Subscriptions to various journals.
  - Report of the Board of Officers [to the American Philosophical Society] upon the formation of an American association for the promotion of the sciences, Febrauary 15, 1839; 6 1/8" x 7 3/4"; American Philosophical Society. Board of officers
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. D.S.: J[ohn] K. Kane. The formation of such an association, under the leadership of the A.P.S., considered inexpedient.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 18, 1839; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Forbes, Philip Jones, 1807-1877
    New York, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Wishes to know the number of volumes of A.P.S. Transactions published, in order to complete set of the New York [Historical?] Society.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 21, 1839; 8" x 10"; Tidyman, Philip
    Charleston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Letter to sympathy upon Vaughan's accident; hopes for recovery. Sends Statutes of South Carolina, III and IV, to A.P.S.
  - Letter to the Committee on the Smithsonian bequest, Feb. 21, 1839; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 25, 1839; 10x8; Cuthbert, John A. (John Albert), 1788-1881
    Hamburg, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Concerning purchases for the library. Refers to Schumacher.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 28, 1839; 10x8; Brewster, Seabury
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Forwards geological report to the APS.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 1, 1839; 5" x 8"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Deposits book from Mr. B. Franklin Mendenhall in the library of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the President and members of the A.P.S., March 1, 1839; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Hughes, Robert Ball, 1806-1868
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Offers to sell bust of Nathaniel Bowditch, which he executed, to A. P. S. for $15. Accepted.